RG 074:049, Coat of Arms Collection
Connecticut State Library
Coat of Arms collection
1904-1936, undated
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut State Library (collector)
3 cubic feet
A collection of coat of arms that include drawings, photostats and paintings.
RG074_049
Multiple
Scope and Content
Includes drawings, photostats, and paintings.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Devices (Heraldry)
Family Names:
Adams family; Atwater family; Bowles family; Borden family; Brownell family; Bullard family; Burr family; Collins family; Cowdrey family; Cutler family; Dawley family; Depasco family; De Peyster family; Doty family; Farren family; Frank family; Geer family; Goodwin family; Humpherey family; Leland family; Lewis family; Lord family; McCleary family; Myers family; Pechin family; Phippen family; Pounds family; Rand family; Root family; Seymour family; Sharp family; Shearer family; Smart family; Spencer family; Stiebar family; Stuart family; Taylor family; Tilden family; Washington family; Watson family; Wells family; Windsor family
Document Types:
Drawings; Paintings
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Accession 1936-009 came to the Connecticut State Library by gift from Mrs. William A. (Mary Jerome Higgins) Semple on July 15, 1936.
Container List
- Accession 1936-009, 1904-1906
  - Lacey, 1904 April 15; watercolor
    Painted by Mary Jerome Higgins.
  - Young, 1906 November; watercolor
- Accession 1982-005, 1932-1936, undated
  - Adams, photostat copy (Item 1)
    Illustration and grant of arms to Dr. Arthur Adams, Trinity College, Hartford, Conn., from the King of Arms, Edinburgh, November 7, 1940.
    Photostat copy was made on 1946 May 24.
  - Adams, photostat copy (Item 2)
    Illustration and grant of arms to Hannah Green Adams, July 8, 1930.
    Back date December 1, 1939.
  - Atwater, 2 copies; colored (Item 3)
    Arms and Crest confirmed to Robert Atwater of Toyton Manor in Lenham by William Harvey Clarenceax, Herald at Arms, in 1564.
    Source: Francis Atwater, New Haven, February 1927.
  - Bolles, colored (Item 4)
    Painted by Charles N. Camp.
    Source: W.G. Andrews, September 17, 1932.
  - Borden, Colored (Item 5)
    Source: W.G. Andres, September 17, 1932.
  - Brownell, 1936 September; 3 copies,; black and white (Item 6)
    Arms granted February 8, 1662, to Sir Robert Dacres, for his wife, Dame Mary Dacres, daughter and heir of John Brownell of the town of Derby.
    Printed by E.E. Brownell, Philadelphia, PA.
  - Bullard, colored (Item 7)
  - Burr, photostat copy (Item 8)
    Granted to Hugh Burr.
  - Burr, photostat copy (Item 9)
  - Collens, photostat copy (Item 10)
    Made from original in possession of Miss J.T. Collins, Hartford, January 19, 1931.
  - Collins, photostat copy (Item 11)
  - Cowdrey, colored (Item 12)
    Received September 29, 1925.
  - Cutler, colored (Item 13)
  - Dawley, 1936 September; 2 copies,; black and white (Item 14)
  - Depasco; Depeyster, colored (Item 15)
  - Doty, black and white (Item 16)
  - Farren, colored (Item 17)
    Painted by Charles L.N. Camp.
  - Geer, colored (Item 18)
  - Goodwin, black and white (Item 19)
    Source: Sadie S. Field, Norwich, March 6, 1953.
  - Humphereys, colored (Item 20)
    Presented to General David Humphereys by Ozias Humphreys, artist of London, about the year 1790 and presented by the widow of William Humphreys, nephew of General David, to Dr. Frederick Humphereys, 1868.
  - Leland, colored (Item 21)
    Painted by Charles L.N. Camp, New Haven, Conn.
    Source: W.G. Andrews, August 1, 1932.
  - Lewis, colored (Item 22)
  - Lord (Item 23)
    Photograph of arms and crest as shown in hatchment at the Connecticut Historical Society.
    Source: Kenneth Lord, NYC, November 10, 1945.
  - Lord, photostat copy (Item 24)
    Colored painting made for the Lord genealogy. Based on description in N.E. Reg. 86:270 and seal on Dorothy Lord's will.
    Source: Kenneth Lord, NYC, November 15, 1945.
  - Lord, colored illustration (Item 25)
    Source: Kenneth Lord, NYC, July 23, 1946.
  - McClary, colored (Item 26)
    M'Clary estate, donor, Oct. 29, 1923.
  - Myers quartering Frank, colored (Item 27)
    Source: W.G. Andrews, August 31, 1932.
  - Pechin, colored (Item 28)
  - Phippen, colored (Item 29)
  - Pond, colored (Item 30)
  - Rand, colored (Item 31)
    Frederick W. Payne, donor, Hartford, October 18, 1926.
  - Root, colored (Item 32)
  - Root - also Winsor, colored (Item 33)
    Wiola Root Cameron, Genealogist, 521 Fifth Ave. New York; 57 Chancery Lane, London.
  - Seymour, colored (Item 34)
  - Sharpe, colored (Item 35)
  - Shearer, colored (Item 36)
  - Smart, colored (Item 37)
    Received July 11, 1977.
  - Spencer, colored (Item 38)
  - Steber, colored (Item 39)
  - Stuart, undated; colored (Item 40)
    Hand drawn.
  - Taylor, colored (Item 41)
  - Tilden, colored (Item 42)
  - Washington, colored (Item 43)
  - Watson, 1932 February 17; 2 copies,; photostat copy (Item 44)
    Painted by James [Watson].
  - Welles, black and white (Item 45)
    Coat of Armour of Simon de Welles, Crusader, AD 1191.
    Donor: Catherine Havens, Hartford. April 18, 1935.